{
    "id": "310470369f42403bb2f230d789eeff85",
    "title": "Adjectives Or Adverbs",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "74b97541eafc4cbd97515b80e95fbc76",
            "title": "Adjectives Or Adverbs",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Janet is a ................................. girl.",
                    "description": "Here the adjective beautiful modifies the noun girl.",
                    "answers": [
                        "beautiful",
                        "beatifully"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The children sang .....................................",
                    "description": "Here the adverb beautifully modifies the verb sang.",
                    "answers": [
                        "beautiful",
                        "beautifully"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The radio is too ................................. Please turn down its volume.",
                    "description": "Adjectives can be the complement of a verb of incomplete predication (is/am/are/was/were). Adverbs cannot be used like this. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "loud",
                        "loudly"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Why are you speaking so ................................?",
                    "description": "We use the adverb loudly to modify the verb speaking.",
                    "answers": [
                        "loud",
                        "loudly"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He is a .................................... learner.",
                    "description": "Fast can be an adjective and an adverb. There is no such word as fastly.",
                    "answers": [
                        "fast",
                        "fastly"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I know him .................................. well.",
                    "description": "Quite is the adverb. There is no such word as quitely.",
                    "answers": [
                        "quite",
                        "quitely",
                        "quietly"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Proofread your work ...................................... before submitting it.",
                    "description": "Here the adverb carefully modifies the verb proofread.",
                    "answers": [
                        "careful",
                        "carefully"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "You have done an ....................................... job.",
                    "description": "Here we use the adjective excellent to modify the noun job.",
                    "answers": [
                        "excellent",
                        "excellently"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I thought I would pass the test ..................................., but I failed after all.",
                    "description": "Here we need the adverb easily to modify the verb pass.",
                    "answers": [
                        "easy",
                        "easyly",
                        "easily"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I have ...................................... had any rest since morning.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "hard",
                        "hardly"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I have been having a lot of headaches of .............................",
                    "description": "Of late is similar to lately.",
                    "answers": [
                        "late",
                        "lately"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "He was very .................................... of the plan.",
                    "description": "Adjectives can be the complement of a verb of incomplete predication (is/am/are/was/were). Adverbs cannot be used like this. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "critical",
                        "critically"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}